RESOURCES/FRAMEWORKS

> Google Analytics

> Wordpress

> Mailchimp

ShopifyBootstrap

> Git

CHARLES KING

- > UX/UI Designer
- > Front-End Developer

3509 Lakeland Drive Austin, TX 78731

978.239.8883 cking@c9db.com c9db.com

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer specializing in UX/UI design. Detail-oriented and driven. Works well with others, both in team and leadership positions. My goal is to create a clear and effective communications channel between organizations and their target audiences, whether through a website, app, structured media posts through third-parties, or all three. Comprehensive and system-based approach to problem solving.

APPLICABLE SKILLS

FRONT END

- > HTML (through HTML5)
- > CSS (through CSS3 including SASS, LESS, and SCSS preprocessing)
- > JavaScript
- > JQuery

SERVER SIDE

- > PHP (familiar)
- > Liquid (based on Ruby)
- > Node.JS (familiar)

RECENT EXPERIENCE

MAY 2017 - PRESENT

TOME, NYC, NY TomeNYC.com

Full-Stack Web Developer (Freelance)

- > Complete site redesign and migration for a fashion brand in NYC including new custom Shopify theme, new custom branded MailChimp campaign, complete product catalog reorganization
- > Documentation and training sessions to enable non-technical team to perform site maintenance and development.

JAN 2016 - MAR 2017

Bento Box, Brooklyn, NY

BentoBox.com, BentoBuild.com, BentoWahiawa.com

Chief of Operations

- > Managed the design, development, and deployment of three websites
- > Set up integrated web applications to coordinate company operations all over the world (hotel booking and operation in Honolulu, Hawaii, furniture design, production and sales in Brooklyn, NY, real-estate development in Nashville, TN)

DEC 2012 - JAN 2016

Black Market Custom, Millbury, MA

BlackMarketCustom.com

Owner & CEO

- > Designed, built, managed blackmarketcustom.com which functioned as an ecom site, a custom quote generator, and a products portfolio
- > All product photography and editing as well as company graphic design

JUN 2008 - DEC 2012

The Bioengineering Group, Salem, MA

IT Systems Admin

> Responsible for maintaining and managing IT infrastructure including multiple domains in secure environments (multiple contracts with USACE requiring military-level security protocols).

EDUCATION

JAN 2007 – MAY 2009

Suffolk University, Boston, MA

Physics & Environmental Engineering

SEP 2006 – DEC 2006 Trinity College, Hartford, CT Physics & Chemistry

REFERENCES

Emily Elliott

Direct manager while working for TOME (MAY 2017 – PRESENT)

Email: emily.jill.elliott@gmail.com

Phone: 405.370.6330

Justin Koziol

Direct manager while working for Bento Box (JAN 2016 - MAR 2017)

Email: jkoziol@bentobox.com

Phone: 808.349.1722

Wendi Goldsmith

Owner, The Bioengineering Group (JUN 2008 – DEC 2012)

Email: sustainabilityvisions@gmail.com

Phone: 617.901.2306